<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Shubham Bansal Technical Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Shubham Bansal Technical Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 03:59:44 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Table Format Series - Apache Iceberg - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/iceberg-table-format-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 03:59:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/iceberg-table-format-part1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction So, after a couple of years of debating whether to jump into the icy waters of Apache Iceberg Table format, I finally mustered up the courage (and the free time, thanks to a long weekend) to dive into understanding it. Spoiler alert: I didn’t freeze—well, maybe just a little, but it was worth it.&#xA;In this post, I’m going to tackle some burning questions that have been floating around my head</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Distributed Cache Series - Part I - Redis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/distributed-cache-series-part-1-redis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 19:36:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/distributed-cache-series-part-1-redis/</guid>
      <description>Introduction For the last couple of weeks, I have been discussing with my colleagues about&#xA;How can we improve the performance of some of our data access?&#xA;I will give you some background about the system so that we know our base tenets throughout this blog.&#xA;Let’s say the system stores the structured data in a database (Amazon DynamoDB) and unstructured data blob in some blobstore (Amazon S3). And, we want to improve the data access latency for both data stores as they provide sub-10ms latency for GET operations.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Poison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 13:43:53 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Poison&lt;/em&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;clean&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;professional&lt;/strong&gt; Hugo theme designed to &lt;strong&gt;captivate&lt;/strong&gt; your readers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also &lt;strong&gt;tiny&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;privacy conscious&lt;/strong&gt;.  No JavaScript frameworks, icon packs, or Google fonts.  No ads or trackers polluting your console window.  &lt;strong&gt;We kept things simple&lt;/strong&gt;.  A little vanilla JavaScript, a dash of CSS, and the power of Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All the static assets for the site (JS files, CSS, and fonts) are located within the theme&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;/assets/&lt;/em&gt; directory.  &lt;strong&gt;That way you know &lt;em&gt;exactly&lt;/em&gt; what&amp;rsquo;s going onto your site&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Check out our demo site&amp;rsquo;s analytics &lt;a href=&#34;https://plausible.lukeorth.com/poison.lukeorth.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to gauge community interest in the theme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
